hello it's September 17th 2020 23. this
video is an overview and an onboarding
for the textbook group specifically
cohort 5 of the active inference
textbook group at the Active inference
Institute
the book we're discussing is active
inference the free energy principle in
mind brain and behavior by Thomas Parr
Giovanni pezula and Carl friston you can
get a hardcover book or as we'll show in
a second This Is An Open Source book so
we can share the PDF for free
this video is mainly going to be an
overview of the sections of this coda
which represent the asynchronous
participation or at least a part of it
for the textbook group
also you can do whatever work you want
in your own workspaces but as we'll see
there are some cool features of having a
shared epistemic Niche or workspace that
enable us to add a lot of value and
connect a lot of dots for each other and
we'll talk about synchronous meetings as
well however interacting with this
document is where all the information is
kept
a directory page covers a few different
areas and pages that you might want to
look at
in the cohorts and meeting section
also this is a total living document
just showing a snapshot at one time
cohort five is just beginning in the
coming week and just to give a little
bit of a scattered plot about people's
background in this figure
on the x-axis is people self-reported
familiarity with active inference across
different registration periods of the
textbook group and on the y-axis
are people self-evaluated familiarity
with green computer science blue biology
and red math and so it just gives a
little bit of a idea so everyone all
learning styles and approaches that
people are going to take will be
welcomed and
hopefully people can participate however
is Meaningful for them
in the page cohort 5 live meetings
there's a table that has the dates and
the times of the meetings that we'll
have that will be recorded for cover
five after the meetings the video
recording will be listed in this column
as a clickable link for example in
cohort four this is what that looks like
um in the first week we're going to have
an onboarding in an overview hopefully
some people will have watched this video
by then however it will be okay if not
following that we'll have two weeks per
chapter going through the first five
chapters
and the meetings alternate time so
people may or may not be able to join
one or both sessions synchronously
cohort four who will be going through
the second half of the textbook have
alternating times in the other direction
so if you prefer to just visit one time
at a weekly rate and hear about
different parts of the textbook since
we're referencing And discussing and
building on shared material then you're
welcome to come to really either of the
ongoing series of synchronous meetings
or watch the video recordings
and
we'll go through a few more of these top
sections and then discuss how different
aspects of the book can be referenced in
questions and in our learning in the
onboarding section there's a little bit
more information
about participation modes
and some sections on learning practices
I won't go into them in this video but
people have added many different ways
and we can always add more of ways that
people felt like they were able to be
actively learning
different ways of learning
in this section
par pazula and first in 2022 textbook
several sections of the textbook or
features of it have been already brought
into this Coda document so in the
chapter section there's a list of the
chapters
and a detailed table of contents
unfolding the chapters
section takes you to a page for each
chapter and for most of the chapters are
all the chapters we have an
overview video maybe a 15 to 25 minute
video with myself and Ali
giving a bit of an overview of the text
of the chapter itself
then there's a table of questions and
for each question
there are ways to
upvote it as interesting and Rise those
up in the discussion and also there's an
expandable section where discourse can
exist on each question and reference a
lot of other things so questions are a
big part of the textbook group it's the
minimal epistemic action
and then there's a lot of discussion
that could be brought into that
questions table otherwise just sort of
open-ended discussion and notes and
questions that people have brought in so
for each chapter
we center around this and in a
synchronous discussions look at the
questions that people bring up
the equation section
you can use control plus and minus or
control and mouse scroll to zoom in or
out in coda
in the equation section there's a table
with all of the equations
with screenshots and latex rendering and
plain text
and also descriptions in discourse for
example equation 2.5 with variational
free energy
also the active inference ontology is
used to give a plain text reading of the
equations and then there's different
discussions about aspects of the
equations
of course everyone's welcome to add
their own pieces not all them are as
built out as some
also there's some experiments into using
the language models
in coda
and the latex plain text
to give math explanations explaining it
to high school student writing code
explaining where it might be important
explaining the variables
asking philosophy questions and also
translating it into different languages
and we can add more languages
the figures page
has a table with all the figures this is
very commonly we want to reference a
specific figure and Coda allows us to do
that by using at and then typing figure
and then figure 4.3 becomes something
that we can
bring up
and that becomes really useful
boxes and table similarly covers the
boxes and table and code has some
discussion and also several dozen
implementations of code for active
inference models for people who want to
explore that
so that's
largely bringing features about the
textbook in
in the discourse section
there's a lot of additional
building and resources that successive
cohorts continue to work on
so there's an underlying large questions
table that's also Broken Out In views
by cohort
so if you want to make sure that it
a questions addressed in a cohort 5
meeting then adding it to this table
it'll all feed into the same underlying
view but that'll help us prioritize
those discussions and if you want to add
a new row you can click into an existing
row and just then just add enter
and everyone is welcome to add questions
ideally before the discussion so that we
can review each other's questions and
upvote ones that are interesting also
begin to add our own thoughts and
relevant resources and further questions
in the discussion section as we're
largely building on each other's
collaboration asynchronously
the weekly meetings are for several
months one to two hours per week
however it's really the work that people
put in in terms of the questions that
they ask and the practices that they
engage in outside of the synchronous
meetings and so asking questions and
building on others and sharing our
perspectives that was one of the most
important ways to do that
depending on interest there's a lot of
work in math learning groups on various
features that people can explore
and this has
various ways that it's been approached
throughout the cohorts ranging from
background and fundamental aspects of
math
all the way on through a lot of rigor
and connecting the dots between
equations in the textbook
in projects people have listed projects
that they want to or are or would work
on and a lot of them have come through a
lot of people have also done things that
aren't shown here but it's a place to
get visibility for your project if
you're looking for collaboration or
anything like that
ideas and insights also can be added to
row by row
they don't need to be questions just any
thoughts that you have resources
has some different resources that
supplement or complement
the textbook itself
future textbook group has an anonymous
feedback form
as well as a lot of discussion about
future ways that we could organize and
Implement textbook groups
and erada has some corrections and some
other
things
lastly the active inference table
section
has a few tables that we reference often
through the at Key encoder that includes
the active inference ontology
some links to other relevant research
paper databases that we've compiled for
other knowledge engineering work
as well as the live streams table the
several hundred live streams
that we often reference as they discuss
relevant papers and topics
so
to kind of overview now there's various
ways to participate in cohort 5 as well
as cohort 4. and not conclude your
synchronous and or asynchronous
participation
if you ever have any questions you can
reach out by email or you can tag
by selecting some text and tagging
active inference Institute
we will uh really look forward to your
participation and good luck with the
textbook group bye